Hey! You hear that?
嘿  你能听到吗
*滋滋声*
All kinds of electronics make this sound.
所有电器都有这种滋滋声
But why? Well, in some cases,
这是为什么呢？有时候
the sound comes from interactions between the wire and the air.
声音是由导线与空气间的相互作用产生的
But in most cases, the answer has to do with how we deliver electricity.
但大多数情况下  其原因跟我们传输电能的方法有关
To power things, we send out particles called electrons.
要让电器动起来  我们需要向它发送“电子”这种粒子
And we call those moving electrons current.
我们把移动的电子称为“电流”
There are different types of current,
电流可分为不同的种类
but many things run on alternating current or A/C.
而大部分电器接受的是交流电  也写作 A/C
Here, as the electrons move along, they periodically reverse direction.
交流电里的电子移动时会周期性地改变方向
Now, here’s the thing: Currents create magnetic fields.
关键点来了：电流会产生磁场
And with alternating current, those fields are constantly changing
而交流电所产生的磁场会不断变化
as the electrons move back and forth.
会随着电子往复而变化
Turns out, that change is enough to push and pull on nearby metal
变化的磁场足以拉扯周边的金属
and make it vibrate.
也就是使其振动
And like a plucked guitar string, that produces sound.
这就像被手拨动的吉他弦  会产生声音
Specifically, in the US, that always gets you a slightly out-of-tune B-flat.
更确切地说  在美国  电线噪音的调子总是略有走音的B♭
That’s because the alternating current here switches 60 times per second,
这是因为美国交流电的频率是60赫兹
欧洲大部、亚太
和非洲的市电频率
是 50Hz
so the metal always vibrates at that frequency — or at a multiple of it.
所以金属的振动频率要么等于这个值  要么就是这个值的倍数
And that gets you this note.
这就会产生这个调子：
*略有走音的B♭*